A Guide to the Intercollegiate Music Association
Johnston Memorial Library, Virginia State University
Special Collections and Archives, Johnston Memorial Library, Virginia State University
The Intercollegiate Music Association 1962
Special Collections and Archives, Johnston Memorial Library, Virginia State University
1982-45
2000 items
Minutes, reports and correspondence of this group which was established in 1962 in order to expand and improve all aspects of music in the schools which belonged to the Central Intercollegiate Athletic Association. ACC # 1982-45
We are the official repository for the materials of The Intercollegiate Music Association. The first transfer of materials was in 1982.
Administrative Information
Access
There are no restrictions.
Organizational History
Two recurring problems in Historical Black Colleges and Universities has been finances and recognition. This association was formed during the era of segregation in an effort to combat these two issues.
The Intercollegiate Music Association was conceived by F.Nathaniel Gatlin E.Ed in 1960. Professor Gatlin called an organizational meeting at Virginia State University in 1960, where the purpose and goals were discussed.
Over the course of the next two years a series of meetings were held whic produced a Constitution and By-laws, and the organization was officially established in 1962. The IMA membership was open for all members of the Central Intercollegiate Athletics Association.
Scope and Content Information
Correspondence, minutes, photographs, and reports documenting how the IMA attempted to fulfill it's goals of 1962.
The Intercollegiate Music Association continues today as an organization in improving music education and operate in the Mid-Atlantic.
Series Description
Series I. Minutes and Reports Board Minutes and those of the annual meetings. Included in the minutes are status reports of the Association arranged chronologically.
Series II. Financial Reports of meetings and correspondence concerning finance. Member school ties and expenses.
Series III. Correspondence, General The day to day operations. Plans for concerts and workshops. Correspondence arranged chronologically.
Series IV. Printed Programs and Newsletters
Series V. Printed Photographs of concerts, workshops and individuals associated with the IMA.
Contents List
- MInutes and Reports
  - Constitution-Suggested (Box-folder 1:1)
  - Proposed Constitution (Box-folder 1:2)
  - Constitution 1960 (Box-folder 1:3)
  - Charter (Box-folder 1:4)
  - Directory of Ex. Board (Box-folder 1:5)
  - Annual Meeting 1-6-1912 (Box-folder 1:6)
  - Minutes 5-13-1962 (Box-folder 1:7)
  - Meeting 1963 (Box-folder 1:8)
  - Ex.Board Meeting 9-3-1963 (Box-folder 1:9)
  - Ex.Board Meeting 1964 (Box-folder 1:10)
  - Minutes 1964 (Box-folder 1:11)
  - Ex.Board 1965 (Box-folder 1:12)
  - MInutes 1965 (Box-folder 1:13)
  - Minutes 3-20-66 (Box-folder 1:14)
  - Annual Meeting 3-12-67 (Box-folder 1:15)
  - Ex.Board Minutes 10-15-1967 (Box-folder 1:16)
  - 7th Annual Meeting 3-10-68 (Box-folder 1:17)
  - 8th Ex. Board Meeting 2-2-69 (Box-folder 1:18)
  - Annual Meeting Minutes 5-11-69 (Box-folder 1:19)
  - Annual Meeting 4-4-70 (Box-folder 1:20)
  - Annual Minutes 4-3-71 (Box-folder 1:21)
  - Ex. Board Meeting 9-4-71 (Box-folder 1:22)
  - 11th Annual Meeting Minutes 3-17/19-72 (Box-folder 1:23)
  - Ex.Board Meeting 5-14-72 (Box-folder 2:24)
  - Ex. Board Meeting 9-9-72 (Box-folder 1:25)
  - Minutes 1971,1972(ALS) (Box-folder 1:26)
  - 12th Annual Meeting Minutes 3-17-73 (Box-folder 1:27)
  - Ex. Board 9-8-73 (Box-folder 1:28)
  - Report 1974 (Box-folder 1:29)
  - Ex. Board Meeting 2-16-74 (Box-folder 1:30)
  - 13th Annual Meeting 2-16-74 (Box-folder 1:31)
  - Ex. Board Meeting 5-11-74 (Box-folder 1:32)
  - General Meeting 2-15,17-75 (Box-folder 1:33)
  - Ex. Board Meeting (Box-folder 1:34)
  - Ex. Comm 1-17-76 (Box-folder 1:35)
  - Ex. Board Meeting 11-13-76 (Box-folder 1:36)
  - General Meeting 2-26-77 (Box-folder 1:37)
  - Ex. Board Meeting 6-13-77 (Box-folder 1:38)
  - Ex. Board Meeting 9-24-77 (Box-folder 1:39)
  - General Meeting 2-19-78 (Box-folder 1:40)
  - Ex. Board Minutes 9-23-78 (Box-folder 1:41)
  - General Board Meeting 2-17-79 (Box-folder 1:42)
  - Ex. Board Meeting 10-20-79 (Box-folder 1:43)
  - Ex. Board Meeting Minutes 9-17-81 (Box-folder 1:44)
  - Ex. Board Meeting 6-26-82 (Box-folder 1:45)
- Financial
  - 3rd Annual Meet and Concert 4-3/5-64 (Box-folder 2:1)
  - 11th Annual Attendance Report 1971-72 (Box-folder 2:2)
  - 13th Annual Meeting Report 1974 (Box-folder 2:3)
  - Programs 14th Annual Meeting 2-14-75 (Box-folder 2:4)
  - Letters (Grauer) 1965-73 (Mar.) (Box-folder 2:5)
  - Financial Report 1967 (Box-folder 2:6)
  - Financial Statements 1971 (Box-folder 2:7)
  - Treasurer Report 1979 (Box-folder 2:8)
  - Correspondence 1960 June-Sept (Box-folder 2:9)
  - Correspondence 1960 Oct-Dec (Box-folder 2:10)
  - Correspondence 1961 (Box-folder 2:11)
  - Programming Comm. 1962 (Box-folder 2:12)
  - Correspondence 1962 Jan-April (Box-folder 2:13)
  - Correspondence 1962 May-Dec (Box-folder 2:14)
  - Minutes and Correspondence April 62-April 63 (Box-folder 2:15)
  - Correspondence April 25- Dec 63 (Box-folder 2:16)
  - Correspondence 3rd Annual Concert 1964 (Box-folder 2:17)
  - Correspondence 1964 (Box-folder 2:18)
  - Correspondence 1965 (Box-folder 2:19)
- Correspondence, General
  - Correspondence 1964 (Box-folder 3:1)
  - Correspondence 1964 March-July (Box-folder 3:2)
  - Correspondence 1965 Jan-Feb (Box-folder 3:3)
  - Correspondence 1965 Mar-Jun (Box-folder 3:4)
  - Correspondence 1966 (Box-folder 3:5)
  - Correspondence 1967 Jan-Feb (Box-folder 3:6)
  - Correspondence 1967 Mar-Apr (Box-folder 3:7)
  - Correspondence 1968 (Box-folder 3:8)
  - Correspondence 1969 Feb-Dec (Box-folder 3:9)
  - Correspondence 1970 (Box-folder 3:10)
  - Correspondence 1971 (Box-folder 3:11)
  - Correspondence 1972 Jan-Sept (Box-folder 3:12)
  - Correspondence 1972 Oct-Dec (Box-folder 3:13)
  - Correspondence 1973 Jan-Feb (Box-folder 3:14)
  - Correspondence 1973 Mar-May (Box-folder 3:15)
  - Correspondence 1973 Jul-Oct (Box-folder 3:16)
  - General Correspondence 1973 Nov-Dec (Box-folder 3:17)
  - Correspondence 1974 Jan-Oct (Box-folder 4:1)
  - Correspondence 1974 (Box-folder 4:2)
  - Correspondence 1975 Jan-Apr (Box-folder 4:3)
  - Correspondence 1975 May-Nov (Box-folder 4:4)
  - Correspondence 1976 Jan (Box-folder 4:5)
  - Correspondence 1977 (Box-folder 4:6)
  - Correspondence 1978 Jan-May (Box-folder 4:7)
  - Correspondence 1978 Jun-Dec (Box-folder 4:8)
  - Correspondence 1978 June-May (Box-folder 4:9)
  - Correspondence 1979 Oct-Dec (Box-folder 4:10)
  - Correspondence 1980 Jan-Apr (Box-folder 4:11)
  - Correspondence 1981 May-Jun (Box-folder 4:12)
  - Correspondence 1982 Jan-Feb (Box-folder 4:13)
  - "A Proposal To The National Endowment For the Performing Arts" 1970 (Box-folder 4:14)
  - Proposal 1970 (Box-folder 4:15)
- Printed
  - Presidents Office 1972 (Box-folder 5:1)
  - Faculty Performers' Forms Projected 1961-62 (Box-folder 5:2)
  - Membership Application 1962 (Box-folder 5:3)
  - Programming Comm 1962-63 (Box-folder 5:4)
  - Calender Of Events 1970-71 (Box-folder 5:5)
  - Confirmations 1971-72 (Box-folder 5:6)
  - Conf. Materials for 1972 (Box-folder 5:7)
  - Materials Conf. 1973 (Box-folder 5:8)
  - Band Director, Choir Director, Chairman 1974 (Box-folder 5:9)
  - Band Procedures 1975 (Box-folder 5:10)
  - Student Delegates 1976 (Box-folder 5:11)
  - Band Members (Box-folder 5:12)
  - Student Roster (Box-folder 5:13)
  - Band Selection 1961 (Box-folder 5:14)
  - 5th Annual Meeting-Band Roster (Box-folder 5:15)
  - Historic Outline (Box-folder 5:16)
  - Newsletters Published 1965-66 (Box-folder 5:17)
  - Newsletters 1974,76 (Box-folder 5:18)
  - Newsletters 1979 Jan (Box-folder 5:19)
  - Programs 1962-66 (Box-folder 5:20)
  - Programs 1966-67 (Box-folder 5:21)
  - Programs 1968-71 (Box-folder 5:22)
  - Programs 1972-74 (Box-folder 5:23)
  - Programs 1975-78 (Box-folder 5:24)
  - Programs 1982,1996 (Box-folder 5:25)
  - Programs-non I.M.A (Box-folder 5:26)
- Photographs
  - Photos 1965 (Box-folder 6:1)
  - Phot's (color) ca.1986 (Box-folder 6:2)
  - Photos (Box-folder 6:3)
  - Photos (Box-folder 6:4)
  - Photos (Box-folder 6:5)
  - Photos (Box-folder 6:6)
  - Photos (Box-folder 6:7)
  - Photos (Box-folder 6:8)
  - Photos-Meeting (Box-folder 6:9)
  - Photos-Music Dept Meeting (Box-folder 6:10)
  - Photo (Box-folder 6:11)
  - Photos-Meeting (Box-folder 6:12)
  - Photos (Box-folder 6:13)
  - Photos (Box-folder 6:14)
  - Photos (Box-folder 6:15)
  - Photos (Box-folder 6:16)
  - Photos (Box-folder 6:17)
  - Photos (Box-folder 6:18)
  - Photos (Box-folder 6:19)
  - Photos (Box-folder 6:20)
  - Photos (Box-folder 6:21)
  - Photos (Box-folder 6:22)
  - Photos (Box-folder 6:23)
  - Photos (Box-folder 6:24)
  - Photos (Box-folder 6:25)
  - Photos (Box-folder 6:26)
  - Photos (Box-folder 6:27)
  - Photos (Box-folder 6:28)
  - Photos (Box-folder 6:29)
  - Photos (Box-folder 6:30)
  - Photos (Box-folder 6:31)
  - Newspaper Clippings (Box-folder 6:32)